But there is a high level of risk in
these kinds of investments. High level
in AI-related
investments you're talking about? Yeah,
I think whether it's TSMC or Facebook or
Nvidia or you name it who is who's
involved in the space and spending
billions in CapEx on on data centers and
chips and infrastructure. This space it
has a lot of potential. There's no doubt
about that. It also carries a lot of
risk.
>> People are talking about this potential
AI bubble. People are worried that now
companies are spending too much. Earlier
it was oh, it's great that tech
companies are spending. That means you
know, they must be [music] making a lot
of money and it's good that they're
investing. Now, you know, the sentiment
has kind of shifted a little bit.
They're like whoa, they're spending too
much now.
>> I've had a 25-plus year history of work
experience in the financial markets. I
actually went through the first dot-com
boom and bust. I saw how much companies
were spending on CapEx back in the early
late '90s into early 2000s which led to
the first dot-com boom and bust. Mhm. So
markets always go through cycles.
There's always a bit of a risk of
overspending, overhype.
I'm super happy to be joined by Chetan
from Franklin Templeton. He is a senior
VP and we are really excited to talk to
you because you guys have been around
for over seven decades. That's correct.
77 to be precise.
>> 77 and
just for me to understand your world a
little better.
What type of decisions do you make every
single day?
I love that question.
I like to think of myself as
I try to allocate my time more
efficiently. So that every decision is
on where can I add the most value to
business development and partnerships
with the firm in the area of digital
assets for Asia Pac. What does that
mean? So partnerships as in you reach
out or they reach out to you and you
negotiate deals. What how
visualize that for me?
>> Yeah, so so basically what do I do which
is the question I get asked at the
dinner table
by my kids as well. So in this world
rather than throwing a lot of buzzwords
out there on tokenization and digital
assets, my main role is to focus on how
do I get more scale and more adoption of
the products that we built.
And to do that I have to do a lot of
outreach with whether it is DeFi
institutions like Web3 platforms,
virtual asset trading platforms, neo
banks or traditional institutions like
banks,
brokers. That's what I I'm trying to
spread the word on what we have, what
tokenization means and actually a lot of
it is on education and awareness to be
quite honest. Let's say you meet my mom.
She does not understand what
tokenization means and what are you
tokenizing?
How would you explain that?
>> My mother-in-law started buying
stablecoins and I had to explain to her,
you know, you you don't actually get a
yield just by buying a stablecoin.
There's ways to get it but what we do is
as a 77-year-old institution, most
people know our name and our brand for
standing for long-standing investments
and a measure of trust in how to get to
goals, personal goals, whether those are
simple investment returns or more
complex financial goals. We provide you
the instruments, the mutual funds or
other products to get there.
Now, tokenization can be looked at
or rather blockchain can be looked at in
two ways. One is the infrastructure
layer. So if your mother was asking me
so what does that mean, I would say
look, the old ways of investing have
been you you go to a bank, you fill out
a paper form, maybe you do it digitally.
She probably is having you have to do it
through her mobile but she's transacting
on old rails. Mhm. The new rails are are
more decentralized, they're fast,
efficient, they're on chain and what
tokenization means is it gives you some
benefits that you wouldn't normally see
through the traditional ways of doing
things. So think of tokenization as one,
an infrastructure layer
and two, there's obviously digital
assets and where you can invest in
crypto. That's the investment layer.
People are talking about this potential
AI bubble. People are worried that now
companies are spending too much. Earlier
it was oh, it's great that tech
companies are spending. That means you
know, they must be making a lot of money
and it's good that they're investing.
Now, you know, the sentiment has kind of
shifted a little bit. They're like whoa,
>> Yeah. they're spending too much now. How
do I look at like how do I interpret
this? So I think your question is
addressing specifically around CapEx
spending around the AI aspect, right?
Which is a which is a bit different than
the area I focus on but I I think I can
address the question in sort of more
general terms. Look, I I've had a
25-plus year history
of work experience in the financial
markets. I actually went through the
first dot-com boom and bust. I saw how
much companies were spending Yeah. on
CapEx back in the early late '90s into
early 2000s which led to the first, you
know, dot-com boom and bust. Mhm. So
markets always go through cycles.
There's always a bit of a risk of
overspending, overhype. And you know,
what actually materializes a few years
later, you know, investors will have to
just be patient and see. But there is a
high level of risk in these kinds of
investments. So um Interesting. Yeah, I
mean
>> High level in AI-related
investments you're talking about? Yeah,
I think whether it's TSMC or Facebook or
Nvidia or you name it who is who's
involved in the space and spending
billions in CapEx on on data centers and
chips and infrastructure.
Um this space is um
it has a lot of potential. There's no
doubt about that. It also carries a lot
of risk. Again, I'm not on the
investment side and nor do I proclaim to
have any insight as to which stocks or
things to buy in this space.
But from his experience you have to sort
of take the
the volatility in stride because that's
kind of that game you're really playing.
It's a high risk, high volatile, high
potentially high outcome game for
investors. Well, in your opinion what
would be a safer bet or what is the big
trend that you are looking at?
>> You know, Web 1.0 which was started
during the early dot-com boom so it was
very static web pages. It was one-to-one
interaction being fed. Web 2.0 became a
lot more dynamic. It was about
e-commerce. It was about videos. It was
about, you know, YouTube, Netflix,
sharing etc.
Web3 was taking that same layer and
decentralizing it such that the chains,
the protocols that all these services
operate on, people could own a piece of
the economic value that those chains
create. So there again I'm going to go
back to the the two pillars I spoke
about. One is the investment layer where
you can invest in these protocols. You
can be a owner of the economics of those
chains and two is the infrastructure
benefits that tokenization can bring to
industries like us, like the asset and
wealth management industry where we're
creating products, financial products
for investors to use that are more
efficient, faster, a better experience
and
overall carry better benefits and an
evolution of how they've traditionally
been taking on financial products. Do
you think in a couple of years people
will just see blockchain as, you know,
type kind of ledger, asset ledgers
instead of something that's, you know,
me- memified and exciting. It's more
like an infra now. That's exactly right.
It is part of it is exactly
infrastructure. It is a decentralized
ledger. That's the beauty of it.
And these protocols or chains allow you
to share in the economics of that
infrastructure.
Now, specifically with asset and wealth
management, the benefit is
again cheaper, better, faster. We can
>> feel it as, you know, investors? Like to
you you can see the back end or you can
you know the data, right? But do users
actually feel the speed or do they
really feel that it's cheaper?
Cuz you have a lot of crypto natives
understand this in and out. They know
how blockchain works. That's why they're
investing in the native tokens.
But a lot of the wider world doesn't
understand how crypto works. So there's
a bit of an education awareness.
Question though is do they really need
to understand? Like you don't really
need to understand how a mutual fund
works, right? You just care about as an
investor generally, you want the return,
you want to understand the risk and you
want to get in and out. Liquidity,
performance and active management.
Potentially even passive management if
you just want exposure to the markets.
So the the key thing for investors to
think about in this space is
it is cheaper. It can be much cheaper
because the infrastructure that we've
built around
mutual funds lowers some of the costs
associated with how mutual funds work.
And again, you don't need to get into
nitty-gritty of, you know, transfer
agent or shareholder services. I've
never asked any had any investor come up
and ask, hey, what are your shareholder
servicing fees?
I don't think they even know that. But
that's not the point. They they don't
need to know that necessarily.
We can make it cheaper. We can make it
faster. We can make the experience. So
one of the things I want to talk about
today is where this is all going. We're
not there yet. The potential for
everyone to hold a digital wallet
and hold different assets and do
portfolio construction and monitoring in
a very centralized way.
That's an evolution of the experience
that's really never been had before in
the Web 2.0 world. So we do see the
experiential level benefits of
blockchain
as being a potential benefit that
investors will understand as to how they
move money, how they manage their assets
and liabilities and how they can do it
seamlessly through a centralized wallet.
Would you say that tokenization, the
term, has only been discussed
within the industry?
Retail investors or people that are
actually buying these products, they
don't ask about it. Or because like you
said, they don't have to understand it.
Correct. I think a lot of the And you
got to keep in mind, this is still an
evolving industry. It is a very Yeah.
>> uh tokenization projects and launches
have been a little bit more recent in
the last few years. So, what was earlier
on an experimentation and and
development of proof of concepts are now
turning into larger scale projects. Now,
you got to get retail involved because a
lot bulk of the assets do sit with the
retail. Actually, there's another
benefit for retail. For example, um if
you could only invest in a money mutual
fund for a 5,000 or 1,000 US dollars,
today we can get it to you as low as
$20. So, it expands the whole
possibilities of financial exclusion
inclusion, rather. Um
more greater participation in the
markets
um and and in markets around the world.
So, I do think investors may not
necessarily understand all the
technology behind it, but they can
certainly benefit from it. What type of
blockchains are suitable in this
tokenization world? Is it, you know, how
fast they are? Is it what what are you
looking at? There there are many
different factors in uh sort of
evaluating chains and their the relative
value to each other. Um speed,
governance, security, uh authentication,
auditability.
Um and we as a firm are uh I guess we've
been pioneers in this space. We and and
credit to uh some of our partners here,
many of whom are here today. Uh we work
across 10 different chains today.
Uh we did start with Stellar and that is
uh a So, mostly our default chain
products are on Stellar. Would you
explain why Stellar? Well,
Stellar is a pretty simple,
cost-effective, and secure transmission
chain. We can do transactions at a
relatively fast pace. Okay. Um for low
entry minimum tickets,
uh as well as low transaction costs.
Which was I talking about earlier, the
benefits of tokenization. Well, one of
the benefits could be cost. And cost as
in
the the shareholder servicing fees that
are held by the transfer agent or run by
the transfer agent. So, when you lower
those costs, the end investor benefits.
They could benefit anywhere between 5 to
15 basis points. I'm just giving an
indicative illustrative example here.
Um but those are some of the benefits
like a chain like Stellar could bring to
the table.
Are you looking at how decentralized a
chain is? Does that matter to you?
We are generally focused on uh public
chains. Mhm. Uh
so, by by virtue of
When you say decentralization, chains
are
as long as they've got a public
participation by different validators
and miners,
they are by default decentralized.
Unless they're on a private network
which is controlled by only a few set of
parties. And we generally don't work on
private chains. There are exceptions to
that.
Um but our philosophical view on this
from the since the start has been the
beauty of blockchain is it enables
decentralization and economic
participation and the value of those
chains. And um yeah, so for those
reasons we're we're very much in favor
of public. Since we're on that topic,
why don't companies just come up with
their own chain? So, they have, you
know, total control. Yeah, so keep in
mind these chains require um
you know, you you've got to set
governance standards. Uh you got to do
the programming. You've got, you know, I
am not a uh I'm I'm not a computer
science guy. I'm not that guy devving on
these chains. So, keep in mind the
the there's a level of technical
astuteness in how to develop a chain
Yeah.
Um it's not so easy to create a new
chain. I mean, think about the potential
for hacking, for example. If you don't
design it just right, you lose entire
trust of that entire chain. Mhm. Um and
we rather focus on our core competence
as an asset manager. What what we are
here for is not to be another chain.
We're
we're we rather work on the rails that
exist,
um but make sure that those rails give
the benefit to the end client and the
end investor. Yeah.
How can you tell a good investor from a
great investor? I think it's about
diversification. Okay. And um there are
many models you could I don't think I
have a great answer to that question
because
ultimately
the question presupposes that someone
can be measured at the end of a certain
amount of time relative to other
investors
in the capacity of allocation. Yeah.
That's certainly doable. You you know,
you can look at Morningstar ratings. You
can look at Morningstar metrics. You can
pick the top quartile funds based on the
balanced funds that have diversified
asset allocation and say,
"This fund did great over 20 years. It
must be the best capital allocator out
there." You know, AI is so different
from how we used to grow up.
>> Right. What are some, you know, advice
you could give really young kids or
young people nowadays? What type of, you
know, core ability or core skills
should they develop in this, you know,
very ever-changing world?
>> Right. Yeah. Uh that's that's a great
question. As I I am I'm preparing for my
daughter's entry into ninth grade and
she's doing her course selections and I
keep thinking about, well, well, you got
to do math and physics and chemistry and
biology cuz, you know, you these are the
and obviously computer science. But I I
take a step back. I mean, joking aside,
um
I think you do need to have some
technical astuteness. Okay. You do you
need to be quantitatively and
technically, you know, you don't have to
be great at every single subject out
there. But pick one or two
science or math-related subjects.
Whether that's, you know, math or
computer science or physics, whatever.
And then combine that with a bit of
human EQ and IQ and understanding how to
deal with uh people. Mhm. I think one of
the biggest risks I see for this
generation is the lack of um I have to
say I every time I see a kid on a phone,
Aw. it makes me uh you know, I believe
like what Australia and Spain and Mexico
and other countries are doing is great
because you got to get them off the
phone. You got to get them more attuned
with how to interact with each other.
Mhm. Um and I believe that still that
human interaction combined with
technical astuteness is going to be the
the differentiator for
for peo- for individuals to succeed in
life. Off camera, I was talking to um a
gentleman. He's interviewing a lot of
young people that wants to join his
company and
they don't really have the people skills
anymore. Mhm.
And I think that kind of echoes what
you're saying, right?
>> And just how to relate to people, how to
understand what their concerns are. Have
you EQ, right? You know,
>> Right. I sense something's bothering
you. How could I maybe address what what
we could do together to help you? For
example. You know, that's just a uh
basic example. That sounds like
something so easy, but yeah, you're
right.
>> Right. Right. And it's hard to teach a
kid who's going to be on the phone every
time, you know, maybe tries or turns
away from
how the world really works. So, maybe in
the world of AI,
the real core skills people should
really focus on is the things that AI
cannot do. Like love or understanding
or, you know, empathy. Yes. Yeah, I
think there was a great um
video from Jensen Huang as well. He was
asked a similar sort of similar
question. So,
>> Yeah.
Yeah, I'm sort of borrowing and
paraphrasing it. I I'll attribute it to
him really. But he said, you know, it's
not just about technical smarts. It's
about um
knowing having some degree of
technical astuteness, Mhm. but also
complementing that with human empathy,
human interaction, and and knowing how
to deal with people and problems and and
resilience,
really.
Well, after talking to you, I definitely
have gained a lot of new insights into
this industry and also Well, we'll see
in 20 years, right? If I'm right or
wrong, I don't know. I I think you're
right. I think you're right. Cuz right
now a lot of, you know, young people are
asking AI how to answer questions that
are being asked by AI. For example, if
we're we're talking to each other online
and and I'm not really sure what you
mean, I ask my AI to reply to you and
you probably do the same. So,
I have to admit I haven't used it yet,
but I'm I'm I've seen some of that being
used. But yes. Yeah.
Well, thank you so much for spending
this time and it's so great talking to
you. Oh, thank you, Bonnie. A pleasure
to be on the channel. Thank you.
Bye-bye.